A Guide to the David Rockefeller Fund records FA1774
Rockefeller Archive Center
The David Rockefeller Fund records
1989-2006, and undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
David Rockefeller Fund
Rockefeller, David (1915-2017)
FA1774
9.39 Cubic Feet 7 record storage boxes and 1 half-letter document box
Conditions Governing Access
Records ten years old and older are open for research. Brittle or damaged materials are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
The David Rockefeller Fund was created in 1989 by David and Peggy Rockefeller to support charitable organizations in communities, outside of New York City, where they had homes (particularly in Maine and in Columbia and Westchester counties in New York). In 2001, David Rockefeller expanded the fund and encouraged his children and grandchildren to become active participants in its philanthropic direction and grantmaking.
The Citizenship Program was the name the fund gave its community grantmaking, from 1990-2009. Starting in 2001, the fund added a second program area, the Family Interest Program, which made grants in Arts and Education, Criminal Justice, and the Environment. The David Rockefeller Fund continues to concentrate on the Arts, Criminal Justice, and the Environment in its current grantmaking. The fund has also regularly encouraged and supported the special philanthropic interests of individual family members as well as their collaborative projects.
Scope and Contents
The David Rockefeller Fund records include materials relating to its Citizenship Program grants and Family Interest Program grants (from 2001-2006), as well as to Discretionary grants (from 2001-2005). It also contains Board meeting and other records from 1989-1992 and from 1999-2004.
Arrangement
Intellectually arranged in series by program or record type.
- David Rockefeller Fund Administrative and Board Records, 1; 5.26 Cubic Feet 4 record storage boxes
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 2000 November 13 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 2000 November 13 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 2000 November 13 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Meeting Books, 2000 November 13 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2000 November 13 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2000 April 24 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 2000 April 24 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 2000 April 24 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 2000 April 24 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Meeting Books, 2000 April 24 (Box 3)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 1999 November 30 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 1999 November 30 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 1999 November 30 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Follow-Up, 1999 November 30 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Meeting Books, 1999 November 30 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 1999 November 30 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 1999 May 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 1999 May 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 1999 May 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Follow-Up, 1999 May 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Meeting Books, 1999 May 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 1999 May 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Financial Information, 1989-1992 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Annual Meeting Books, 1990-1992 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 1990 January 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - DR's Opening Statements, 1990 January 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 1990 January 10 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Annual Meeting Books, 1990 June 15 (Box 4)
  - Maine Gifts (Not through David Rockefeller Fund), 1990 (Box 4)
  - Dinner for Fifth-Generation Rockefeller Family Members, 1999 October 14 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Declines, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Rockefeller and Company Response to Questions, 1993 Fall (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Mid-Year Reports, 1992-1999 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Board Book, 2002 May 8 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 2002 May 8 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 2002 May 8 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2002 May 8 (Box 4)
  - Untitled Folder (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Follow-Up Memo to Family, 2002 December 12 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 2002 December 12 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 2002 December 12 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2002 December 12 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Board Books, 2002 December 12 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Family Proposals, 2002 (Box 4)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Discretionary (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Discretionary Fellowships, 2001 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Discretionary Grants, 2002 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Discretionary Grants, 2003 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Discretionary Grants, 2004 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Discretionary Grants, 2005 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Matching Grants, 2003 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Matching Grants, 2004 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Matching Grants, 2005 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 2001 May 29 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 2001 May 29 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2001 May 29 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 2001 May 29 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting, 2001 November 28 (Box 5)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting, 2001 November 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 2001 November 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 2001 November 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 2001 November 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Board Book, 2001 November 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2001 November 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting, 2001 November 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Year-End Report (Empty Report), 2001 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting (Empty Folder), 2001 May 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Board Book, 2004 December 17 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 2004 December 17 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Correspondence, 2004 December 17 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2004 December 17 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 2004 December 17 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes (Empty Folder), 2004 May 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 2004 May 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2004 May 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Citizen Grantmaking Program, 2004 May 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Annual Meeting, 2004 May 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Board Book, 2004 May 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorizations (First Half 2004 including May 28, 2004 Meeting), 2004 May 28 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting, 2003 December 10 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 2003 December 10 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Family Interest Program Declines (of Groups Strongly Considered), 2003 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 2003 December 10 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Memos and Correspondence, 2003 December 10 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2003 December 10 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Board Books, 2003 December 10 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Correspondence to Family, 2003 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Properties Summary (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting, 2003 June 4 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Minutes, 2003 June 4 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Interim Authorization, 2003 June 4 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Notes, 2003 June 4 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Correspondence, 2003 June 4 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Board Books, 2003 June 4 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund Meeting - Board Book, 2001 May 29 (Box 6)
  - David Rockefeller Fund - Annual Meeting, 2001 May 29 (Box 6)
- Citizenship Grants Program, 2; 4.13 Cubic Feet 3 record storage boxes and 1 half-letter document box
  - Abnaki Girl Schouts (Box 1)
  - Robert Abbe Museum of Stone Age Antiquities (Box 1)
  - 2015:062:001 - Robert Abbe Museum - Slides (Box SF 1)
  - Arcady Music Festival (Box 1)
  - Acadia Wildlife Foundation (Box 1)
  - Bar Harbor Festival Corporation (Box 1)
  - Blaine House (Box 1)
  - Board Network (Box 1)
  - Boy Scouts of America, Katahdin Area Council (Box 1)
  - College of the Atlantic, Beatrix Farrand Garden (Box 1)
  - College of the Atlantic, Natural History Museum (Box 1)
  - College of the Atlantic (Box 1)
  - Community Health and Counseling Services (Box 1)
  - Downeast Horizons (Box 1)
  - Farnsworth Art Museum (Box 1)
  - Frenchboro Future Development Corporation (Box 1)
  - Friends of Acadia (Box 1)
  - Friends of Acadia (Box 1)
  - Wendell Gilley Museum (Box 1)
  - Grate Harbor Maritime Museum (Box 1)
  - Hospice of Hancock County (Box 1)
  - H.O.M.E. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Island Outward Bound School (Box 1)
  - Island Institute (Box 1)
  - Jackson Laboratory (Box 1)
  - Kids' Corner Community Child Care (Box 1)
  - Maine Community Foundation (Box 1)
  - Maine Medical Center (Box 1)
  - Maine Public Broadcasting (Box 1)
  - Maine Time Dollar Network (Empty Folder) (Box 1)
  - Mainstay (Box 1)
  - Mt Desert Festival of Chamber Music Society (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Island Biological Laboratory (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Island (MDI) Alcohol and Drug Abuse Group (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Island High School (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Island Health Care Foundation and MDI Hospital (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Medical Center (Box 1)
  - MDI (Mount Desert Island) Tomorrow (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Island (MDI) Water Quality Coalition (Empty Folder) (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Island (MDI) YMCA (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Island Youth Hostel (Empty Folder) (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Nursery School (Box 1)
  - Maine Coast Heritage Trust (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Summer Chorale - St. Mary's by the Sea (Box 1)
  - Mount Desert Public Health Nursing Association (Box 1)
  - DR Fund - Inquiries and Declines, 2001 (Box 2)
  - DR Fund - Inquiries and Declines, 2000 (Box 2)
  - DR Fund - Inquiries and Declines, 1999 (Box 2)
  - DR Fund - Referrals, Not Funded (Box 2)
  - DR Fund - Inquiries and Declines, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Columbia County Fire Companies (Box 2)
  - United Way of Columbia and Greene Counties (Box 2)
  - Olana Partnership (Box 2)
  - Livingston Free Library (Box 2)
  - Germantown Library (Box 2)
  - Columbia Memorial Hospital (Columbia - Greene Hospital Foundation) (Box 2)
  - Columbia Land Conservancy (Box 2)
  - Boy Scouts of Westchester and Putnam Counties (Box 2)
  - Caramoor - Center for Music and the Arts (Box 2)
  - Children's Hospital, Westchester County Medical Center (Box 2)
  - Fairview - Greenburg Community Center - "The Net" (Box 2)
  - Family Service of Westchester (Box 2)
  - Friends of Parks, Recreation, and Conservation in Westchester (Box 2)
  - Friends of Rockefeller State Park (Box 2)
  - Girl Scouts of Westchester-Putnam (Box 2)
  - Green Chimneys Children's Services (Box 2)
  - Hudson Valley Writers Center (Box 2)
  - Larchmont Mamaroneck Hunger Task Force, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Orpheus Chamber Orchestra (Box 2)
  - Pocantico Hills Foundation (Box 2)
  - Puppies Behind Bars (Box 2)
  - Riverkeeper (Box 2)
  - Salvation Army of Greater New York - Westchester Emergency Feeding Program (Box 2)
  - Teatown Lake Reservation (Box 2)
  - Union Church of Pocantico Hills (Box 2)
  - United Way of the Tarrytowns (Box 2)
  - Warner Library (Box 2)
  - 2015:062:002 - Warner Library - Photographs (Box SF 1)
  - Westchester Fire Departments (Box 2)
  - Northeast Harbor Library (Box 2)
  - Safe Family Exchange (S. A. F. E.) (Empty Folder) (Box 2)
  - Untitled Folder (Box 2)
  - St. Joseph's College (Box 2)
  - Summer Field Studies (Box 2)
  - Swan's Island Educational Society (Box 2)
  - Union Congregational Church of Seal Harbor (Box 2)
  - Willowind - Maine Adaptive Sport and Recreation (Box 2)
  - Bethel Homes (Box 2)
  - Board of Education (Box 2)
  - Boys and Girls Club of Northern Westchester (Box 2)
  - Maine Sea Coast Missionary Society (Box 3)
  - Seal Harbor Library Association (Box 3)
  - Seal Harbor Neighborhood House Nursery School (Box 3)
  - Seal Harbor Village Improvement Society (Box 3)
  - Ambulance Fund, Northeast Harbor Fire Company (Box 3)
  - Maine Fire Departments (Box 3)
  - Neighborhood House (Box 3)
  - Portland Museum of Art (Box 3)
  - Mount Desert Township Scholarship Program (Box 3)
  - Natural Resources Council of Maine (Box 3)
  - Nature Conservancy, Maine Chapter (Box 3)
  - Historic Hudson Valley (Box 3)
  - Historical Society of the Tarrytowns (Box 3)
  - Marymount College, Tarrytwon (Box 3)
  - Elizabeth Mascia Child Care Center (Box 3)
  - North Tarrytown Open Door Family Health Center (Box 3)
  - Phelps Memorial Hospital Center (Box 3)
  - Planned Parenthood of Hudson Peconic (Box 3)
  - Scenic Hudson (Box 3)
  - Soundview Preparatory School (Box 3)
  - Westchester Land Trust (Box 3)
  - Family YMCA at Tarrytown (Box 3)
- Family Interest Grants Program, 3; 3.94 Cubic Feet 3 record storage boxes
  - Center for Alternative Sentencing and Employment Services (CASES) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - College of the Atlantic (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001 (Box 5)
  - Center for Court Innovation (CCI) (DR Fund), 2003-2005 (Box 5)
  - Coalition for Hispanic Family Services ((DR Fund - Family Interest), 2003-2004 (Box 5)
  - Department of Correction Discharge Conference (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2003 (Box 5)
  - Dreamyard (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2002-2005 (Box 5)
  - Friends of Island Academy (CJS) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition (LP and C) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - Island Institute (LP and C) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2003-2004 (Box 5)
  - Materials for the Arts (MFTA) (DR Fund), 2003-2005 (Box 5)
  - Northwest Atlantic Marine Alliance (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2002 (Box 5)
  - Osborne Association (DR Fund), 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - Predator Conservation Alliance (DR Fund), 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - Women's Prison Association and Home, Inc. (CJS) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2003 (Box 5)
  - Studio Museum in Harlem (Arts and Education) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - Starfish Theatreworks (Arts and Education ) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2003 (Box 5)
  - El Museo del Barrio (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - American Wildlands (AWL) (DR Fund), 2004-2006 (Box 6)
  - Scenic Hudson (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001 (Box 7)
  - Red Tomato (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2002 (Box 7)
  - Tumbledown Conservation Alliance (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2002 (Box 7)
  - WNYC (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001 (Box 7)
  - All Species (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - Northern Forest Alliance (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2002 (Box 7)
  - Center for Arts Education (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Columbia Land Conservancy (C and LP) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001 (Box 7)
  - Conservation International (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001 (Box 7)
  - Conservation Law Foundation (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001 (Box 7)
  - Charles Darwin Research Station and Charles Darwin Foundation (C and LP) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Lower Manhattan Cultural Council (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001 (Box 7)
  - Puppies Behind Bars (CJS) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001 (Box 7)
  - Art Start (Arts and Education) (DR Fund - Family Interest), 2001-2002 (Box 7)